James Collin Jones

Full Stack Software Developer | Columbus, Ohio | 859-539-5203

Email: jamescollin.jones.jcj@gmail.com Portfolio: https://jcollinjones.netlify.app
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/j-collin-jones/
GitHub: https://github.com/JCollinJones25

Summary

Software Engineer providing efficient software solutions for everyday use. Focus on component based development, concise and efficient programming, and user-friendly design. Background in police work and experience in collaborating on teams, overcoming unique challenges under stress, and understanding people from different walks of life.

<u>Skills</u>

React | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Sass | Bootstrap | Salesforce | PostgreSQL | Microsoft SQL Server | MongoDB | Express.js | Node.js | Python | Django

Relevant Experience

Technical Support Agent | AutoSweet | January 2023 - Present

- Troubleshoot client accounts in Salesforce
- Use SQL queries to access Jet Database using Microsoft SQL Server

Software Engineering Teaching Assistant | General Assembly | August 2022 - Present

- 100+ students taught with a 85% graduation rate
- Taught full stack development technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express.js, Node.js, Python, Django, SQL and NoSQL databases
- Hosted office hours for a software engineering course for the purpose of providing troubleshooting support

Portfolio - https://jcollinjones.netlify.app/

Disclose - Django backend app that allows users to share locations on a map using the MapBox API

- Site: https://disclose-locations.herokuapp.com/ | Git: https://github.com/JCollinJones25/disclose

Trade Tracker - React app allowing the user to search stock market data from a stock market API

- Site: https://trade-tracker-stocks.herokuapp.com/ | Git https://github.com/JCollinJones25/trade_tracker

IMDb Clone - Full stack CRUD application built with the MEN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js) MVC framework

- Site: https://collins-imdb.herokuapp.com/movies | Git: https://github.com/JCollinJones25/IMDb

Travel Buddy - PERN application (PostgreSQL, Express.js, React, Node.js) which allows the user to organize travel plans

- Site: https://travelbuddy-planner.netlify.app/ | Git: https://github.com/JCollinJones25/travelbuddy frontend

<u>Professional Experience</u> - SKILLS: Communications, Procedures, Public Safety, Problem Solving, Deescalation

Police Officer | Fayette County Public Schools | March 2021 - January 2022

- Made a positive impact on students and staff at 6 Lexington high schools
- Conducted criminal investigations from start to finish which includes evidence collection, interviews, and disposition
- Involved in creating procedure for school safety and prevention of dangerous incidents

Police Officer | Lexington Police Department | January 2020 - March 2021

- E. C. Hale Scholastic Award from the Lexington Police Academy received in September of 2020 for ranking top of the class out of 25 police recruits
- Commander's Letter of Commendation received in December of 2020 for involvement in an investigation leading to a high profile arrest

Education

General Assembly Software Engineering | Remote | March 2022 - June 2022 University of Kentucky | Lexington, KY | August 2016 - December 2019

- Bachelor's of Arts in Political Science | Minor in Criminology